Franz Boas Papers 1862-1942 Mss.B.B61.inventory02 Mss.B.B61.inventory02
American Philosophical Society
Franz Boas Papers: Inventory (B)
1862-1942
Mss.B.B61.inventory02
American Philosophical Society
1.0 section
This is part of the large inventory for the Franz Boas Papers (Mss B B61). For complete information concerning this collection, please view the Collection Description.
Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
Scope and Contents note
Due to the size of the collection, the content for Series I has been divided into multiple inventories. Please follow the links below to browse the inventories.
Inventories
Correspondents A
Correspondents B
Correspondents C
Correspondents D
Correspondents E-G
Correspondents H
Correspondents I-K
Correspondents L
Correspondents M
Correspondents N-Q
Correspondents R
Correspondents S
Correspondents T-V
Correspondents W-Z
- Franz Boas Papers - Correspondents B
  - B?, R? (Box 3)
    Scope and Contents note
    (Ruth Benedict? Ruth Bunzel?)
    - To Boas, 1937 May 5; 2p
  - Babbitt, E.H. (Box 3)
    - To Boas, 1917 Nov. 1
  - Babcock, H.D. (Box 3)
    - From Boas, 1931 Feb. 16; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Feb. 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 May 22; 2p
  - Bach, Matthew G. (Box 3)
    - To Boas, 1938 Jan. 28; 1p
  - Bachenberg, B. (Box 3)
    - To Boas, 1906 Apr. 6; 1p
  - Bacon, Alice M. (Box 3)
    - To Boas, 1898 Dec. 20; 4p
  - Bacon, Arbrot? (Box 3)
    - to Holmes, W.H., 1906 May 18
  - Badman, T. (Box 3)
    - From Boas, 1933 June 20; 1p
    - From Boas, 1934 Feb. 12; 1p
    - From Boas, 1934 Oct. 18; 1p
    - From Boas, 1935 Jan. 2; 1p
    - From Boas, 1935 Jan. 14; 1p
    - From Boas, 1935 Mar. 4; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 June 15; 1p
      - enc. Gutstadt, R.E., 1934 Oct. 18; 1p
      - enc. Rubinow, I.M., 1934 Oct. 25; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Jan. 3; 1p
      - enc. Rubinow, I.M., 1935 Jan. 12; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Jan. 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Feb. 13; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Mar. 5; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Mar. 11; 1p
    - T.B. -- to Gutstadt, R.E.
      - enc., 1935 Mar. 11; 1p
    - T.B. -- from Gutstadt, R.E.
      - enc., 1933 June 8
    - T.B. -- from Rubinow, I.M.
      - enc., 1934 Oct. 23
    - T.B. -- from Rubinow, I.M., 1935 Jan. 10
  - Baehr, George (Box 3)
    - From Boas, 1934 July 2; 1p
    - From Boas, 1935 Oct. 23; 1p
    - From Boas, 1935 Dec. 2; 1p
    - From Boas, 1935 Dec. 4; 1p
    - From Boas, 1935 Dec. 9; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 Jan. 15; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 Jan. 27; 1p
    - From Boas, 1937 Mar. 8; 1p
    - To Boas, 1934 June 28; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Dec. 3; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Dec. 5; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Jan. 21; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Jan. 24; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 Mar. 10; 1p
  - Baentir, E.M. (Box 3)
    - From Boas, 1914 Feb. 6; 3p
    - From Boas, 1914 Nov. 13
    - To Boas, 1914 Feb. 18
  - Baer, Werner (Box 3)
    - Vita, 1936 Dec.?; 1p
  - Baerwald, P. (Box 3)
    - From Boas, 1925 Feb. 17; 1p
    - From Boas, 1925 Mar. 2; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 June 12; 1p
    - see letter dated Oct. 4/33 to Warburg, Paul from FB, 1933 Oct. 4; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Oct. 4; 2p
    - From Boas, 1933 Dec. 4; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Dec. 12; 1p
    - To Boas, 1925 Feb. 28; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 June 13; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Oct. 19; 1p
  - Baetmann?,? (Box 3)
    - 1932 Jan. 28, 3p
  - Baginsky, P. (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1934 June 17; 2p
    - PB -- from Gerlich
      - enc. above, 1933 Apr. 2
    - PB -- from J. Bell and C.M. Purin
      - enc. above, 1934 June 13
  - Bagley, W.C. (Box 4)
    - from Rautenstrauch, W., 1942 Feb. 9
  - Bagster-Collins, D. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1935 Oct. 22; 1p
  - Bagster-Collins, E.W. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1934 Oct. 9; 1p
  - Bahnson, K. (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1895 July 30; 2p
  - Bailey, C.A. (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1931 Feb. 11; 2p
  - Bailey, H.C. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1924 Apr. 8; 1p
  - Bailey, J.W. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1941 Aug. 13; 1p
  - Bailey, Lucy (Box 4)
    - To Boas
    - see Josephine Junkin, 1927 May 31
  - Baillou, R.S. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1928 Jan. 16; 1p
    - From Boas, 1928 Jan. 27; 1p
    - From Boas, 1928 Feb. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1928 Jan. 17; 1p
    - To Boas, 1928 Jan. 31; 2p
    - To Boas, 1928 Feb. 8; 1p
    - To Boas, 1929 Aug. 13; 1p
    - To Boas, 1929 Nov. 12; 4p
    - To Boas, 1931 Jan. 19; 7p
  - Bains, G. (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1917 Feb. 13
  - Bainton, Roland H. (Box 4)
    - see FB, open letter, 1938 Jan.
    - see FB, open letter, 1940 Dec. 5; 1p
    - see FB, open letter, 1941 Nov. 7; 1p
  - Baird, Spencer Fullerton (Box 4)
    - Letter of recommendation for FB, 1886 Sept. 9
  - Baker, A.C. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1920 Dec. 31; 1p
  - Baker, Edith M. (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1937 Oct. 13; 1p
  - Baker, Frank (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1898 Dec. 28
    - From Boas, 1902 Mar. 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1898 Dec, 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1898 Dec, 22
    - To Boas, 1898 June 2 & June 8; 2p
    - Open Letter, 1939 Dec.?; 1p
      General note
      (Frank E. Baker) not same
  - Baker, J.C. (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1937 Sept 8; 1p
  - Baker, L. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1914 Jan. 13
  - Baker, Leonard T. (Box 4)
    - see FB, 1938 Jan.
  - Baker, M.L. (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1913.Nov. 15; 3p
    - To Boas, 1914 Jan. 9
    - To Boas, 1914 Feb. 7
  - Baker, Mary Eloise (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1938 Aug. 26; 1p
  - Baker, T.S. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1931 Sept. 1; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Aug. 10; 1p
  - Baker, W.S. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1898 Dec. 28; 1p
    - To Boas, 1898 Dec. 22; 1p
  - Bakhmetieff, G. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1914 May 4; 2p
    - To Boas, 1914 May 8
  - Bakwin, H. (Box 4)
  - Bakwin, Harry (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1931 Oct. 20; 1p
    - From Boas, 1931 Nov. 10; 1p
    - From Boas, 1939 Feb. 6; 1p
    - From Boas, 1941 Dec. 19; 1p
    - To Boas, 1930 Feb. 3; 1p
    - To Boas, 1930 June 30; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Oct. 23; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Nov. 18; 1p
    - To Boas, 1932 Dec. 3; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 Feb. 17; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 Dec. 23; 1p
  - Balamuth, Lewis (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1941 June 2; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 May 29; 1p
  - Balch, E.G. (Box 4)
    - open letter enc., 1918 Apr 3
    - with Barnes, H.E., 1918 July 8; 1p
  - Balch, E.H. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1938 May 23; 1p
  - Balden, H.M. (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1917 Feb. 1; 2p
  - Baldus, H. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1932 Apr. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1932 Mar. 25; 2p
    - To Boas, 1932 Apr. 17; 1p
  - Baldwin, A.E. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1914 Nov. 23; 2p
  - Baldwin, B.T. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1917 Oct. 2; 2p
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 18; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 21; 1p
    - To Boas, 1917 Sept 24
    - To Boas, 1920 Sept 16; 1p
  - Baldwin, C.S. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1916 June 6; 2p
    - C.S.B. -- to Barnard Coll. Provost, 1923 Apr. 9; 1p
  - Baldwin, J. Mark (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1909 Oct. 13; 2p
    - From Boas, 1912 Dec. 10
    - To Boas, 1909 Oct. 26
    - To Boas, 1912 Apr. 19
    - To Boas, 1912 Apr. 23
    - To Boas, 1912 Dec. 7
    - To Boas, 1913 Oct. 13; 1p
  - Baldwin, R.N. (Box 4)
    - 1933 Jan. 23
    - From Boas, 1924 Oct. 10; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Jan. 26; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Sept. 11; 1p
    - From Boas, 1934 Nov. 3; 1p
    - From Boas, 1941 Apr. 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Mar. 25; 1p
    - To Boas, 1932 Mar. 25; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Oct. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Jan. 20; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Jan. 24; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Jan. 27; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Sept. 5; 1p
    - To Boas, 1934 Nov. 2; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 Apr. 14; 1p
    - see Whitie, W.A., 1939 Dec.?
    - R.N.B. -- to Frances McKee, 1941 Mar. 6; 1p
  - Baldwin, R.W. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1917 July 30; 2p
    - To Boas, 1917 July 26
  - Balen, J.C.F. (Box 4)
    - to Holmes, W.H., 1911 Feb. 5; 2p
  - Balfour, Henry (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1903 Dec. 1; 1p
    - To Boas, 1890 June 13; 1p
    - To Boas, 1890 Nov. 18; 1p
  - Balk, R. (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1924 Aug. 27; 1p
  - Ballanta, N.G.J. (Box 4)
    - enc. with Ames, E.R., 1926 Aug. 5; 2p
  - Ballantine, Arthur, Jr. (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1940 Dec. 10; 1p
  - Ballard, A.C. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1928 Jan. 27; 1p
  - Ballesteros, A. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1934 Oct. 29; 1p
  - Ballesteros-Gaibrois, Manuel (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1936 June 19; 2p
  - BalliviC!n, A. (Box 4)
    - To Lichtenstein, W., 1918 Apr. 23; 1p
  - Balokovic, Zlatko (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1942 June 1; 1p
    - From Boas, 1942 June 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1942 May 23; 1p
    - To Boas, 1942 June 8; 1p
    - To Boas, 1942 June 13; 1p
  - Balser, Paul (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1942 Mar. 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1942 Feb. 9; 2p
  - Bally, C. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1931 Feb. 9; 2p
    - To Boas, 1930 June 18; 1p
    - To Boas, 1930 Oct. 4; 4p
    - To Boas, 1931 Jan. 30; 1p
    - C.B. -- to J. Schrijnen, 1928 June 23; 2p
  - Balza, A. (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1910 Mar. 30
  - Bamberg, G. (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1888 Oct. 25; 1p
  - Bamberger, L. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1934 Feb. 5; 2p
    - To Boas, 1934 Feb. 6; 1p
  - Banco Nacional de México (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1911 May 13
    - From Boas, 1911 June 12
    - From Boas, 1913 Nov. 20
    - To Boas, 1912 Jan. 25
    - To Boas, 1912 Apr. 16
    - To Boas, 1912 Apr. 23
    - To Boas, 1913 Dec. 11
  - Bancroft, W.D. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1920 Aug. 7; 1p
  - Bandelier, Ad.F. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1906 Mar. 28
    - From Boas, 1907 Jan. 14
    - From Boas, 1908 May 13
    - From Boas, 1908 Apr. 23
    - To Boas, 1905 June20 & 22
    - To Boas, 1905 June 25; 1p
    - To Boas, 1906 July 30; 1p
    - To Boas, 1907 Jan. 9; 1p
    - To Boas, 1908 Apr. 22; 1p
    - To Boas, 1910 Jan. 7
    - A.F.B. -- to Edward Eyre, 1907 Jan. 26
  - Bandelier, F.R. (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1908 Apr. 22
    - To Boas, 1908 May 14
  - Bandermann, W.H.E. (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1934 Nov. 29; 3p
  - Bangs, G.A. (Box 4)
    - from Brandes, S.F., 1933 Nov. 2
  - Bank of British Columbia (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1893 Nov. 8
    - To Boas, 1894 Sept. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1895 Jan. 21; 1p
    - To Boas, 1895 Nov. 8
    - To Boas, 1894 Aug. 17; 1p
  - Banneiji, J.P. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1914 Nov. 27
    - To Boas, 1914 Nov. 24
    - To Boas, 1914 Dec. 3
    - To Boas, 1914 Dec. 3
  - Banning, Hubert (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1904 Nov. 27; 2p
    - To Boas, 1906 May 12
  - Banning, Margaret C. (Box 4)
    - see Brooks, V.W., 1938 Nov. 22
  - Bannwarth, Dr.? (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1893 July 1; 1p
  - Banz, Frederick (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1920 May 17; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Mar 1; 1p
  - Barail, Louis C. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1938 Mar. 3; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 Feb. 28; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 Apr. 13; 1p
  - Baralt, L.A. Jr. (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1919 May 2; 1p
  - Barbeau, C. Marcus (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1914 Feb. 12
    - From Boas, 1915 Jan. 5
    - From Boas, 1916 Oct. 6; 2p
    - From Boas, 1916 Oct. 25
    - From Boas, 1917 Mar. 1
    - From Boas, 1917 Mar. 2; 2p
    - From Boas, 1917 Mar. 14
    - From Boas, 1917 Mar. 14
    - From Boas, 1917 July 23; 2p
    - From Boas, 1917 Sept 13
    - From Boas, 1918 Jan. 14; 1p
    - From Boas, 1918 Jan. 19; 1p
    - From Boas, 1918 Feb. 25; 1p
    - From Boas, 1918 July 23; 1p
    - From Boas, 1918 Aug. 3; 1p
    - From Boas, 1918 Sept 2; 2p
    - From Boas, 1918 Sept 17; 2p
    - From Boas, 1919 Oct. 14; 1p
    - From Boas, 1919 Oct. 28; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 24; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 26; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept 17; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 27; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 17; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Nov. 24; 1p
    - From Boas, 1923 Oct. 9; 1p
    - From Boas, 1923 Oct. 22; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Nov. 29; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Feb. 7; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Apr. 7; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Oct. 14; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Nov. 3; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Nov. 11; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Nov. 21; 1p
    - From Boas, 1939 Feb. 6; 1p
    - From Boas, 1940 Apr. 12; 1p
    - From Boas, 1940 May 13; 1p
    - From Boas, 1940 Aug. 5; 1p
    - To Boas, 1914 Dec. 4; 3p
    - To Boas, 1914 Dec. 26
    - To Boas, 1916 Jan. 15; 2p
    - To Boas, 1916 Jan. 26; 3p
    - To Boas, 1916 Jan. 26
    - To Boas, 1916 July 10; 3p
    - To Boas, 1916 July 22; 2p
    - To Boas, 1916 Aug. 26; 3p
    - To Boas, 1916 Oct. 2 and Oct. 14; 2p
    - To Boas, 1916 Oct. 21
    - To Boas, 1917 Jan. 17; 2p
    - To Boas, 1917 Mar. 3; 2p
    - To Boas, 1917 Mar. 9; 3p
    - To Boas, 1917 Mar. 10
    - To Boas, 1917 Mar. 21; 3p
    - To Boas, 1917 May 2; 19p
    - To Boas, 1917 June 29
    - To Boas, 1917 July 6; 2p and 4p
    - To Boas, 1917 Aug. 14; 5p
    - To Boas, 1917 Sept. 11; 2p
    - To Boas, 1917 Oct. 3; 2p
    - To Boas, 1918 Feb. 22; 2p
    - To Boas, 1918 May 4; 2p
    - To Boas, 1918 May 17; 2p
    - To Boas, 1918 May 18; 2p
    - To Boas, 1918 May 25; 3p
    - To Boas, 1918 June 5; 1p
    - To Boas, 1918 June 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1918 June 12; 2p
    - To Boas, 1918 July 24; 1p
    - To Boas, 1918 July 30; 2p
    - To Boas, 1918 Aug. 24; 2p
    - To Boas, 1918 Sept 10; 3p
    - To Boas, 1918 Sept 18; 4p
    - To Boas, 1918 Oct. 14; 3p
    - To Boas, 1918 Oct. 29; 2p
    - To Boas, 1918 Oct. 29; 3p
    - To Boas, 1919 Sept 17; 2p
    - To Boas, 1919 Oct. 9; 1p
    - To Boas, 1919 Oct. 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1919 Oct. 30; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Mar. 1; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Mar. 22; 3p
    - To Boas, 1920 Mar. 29; 2p
    - To Boas, 1920 May 27; 5p
    - To Boas, 1920 Aug. 3; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Sept 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Oct. 19; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Oct. 19; 2p
    - To Boas, 1920 Oct. 26; 2p
    - To Boas, 1920 Nov. 5; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Nov. 8; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Nov. 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Nov. 27; 1p
    - enc. Tachě, J. DeL. to C.M.B. Feb. 1/22, 1922 Feb. 3; 1p
    - To Boas, 1923 June 16; 2p
    - To Boas, 1923 Oct. 27; 1p
    - To Boas, 1924 Oct. 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1926 Jan. 30; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Dec. 4; 2p
    - To Boas, 1937 Dec. 28; 2p
    - enc. C.M.B. to Dir., Nat'l Mus. Canada Feb. 9/38, 1938 Feb. 10; 2p
    - To Boas, 1938 Apr. 7; 2p
    - To Boas, 1938 Oct. 19; 2p
    - To Boas, 1938 Nov. 8; 3p
    - To Boas, 1938 Nov. 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 June 30; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 Apr. 9; 2p
    - To Boas, 1940 July 30; 1p
    - CMB -- to W.H. Clawson, 1918 June 8; 2p
    - CMB -- to L. Gouin, 1918 Sept. 10; 2p
    - CMB -- to Miss H. Andrews, 1920 Oct. 11; 1p
    - CMB -- to B.C. Edel, 1940 Aug. 9; 1p
    - CMB -- from A. Boulet, 1918 May 14; 1p
    - CMB -- from L. Gouin, 1918 Sept. 4; 1p
    - CMB -- from J. Taché, 1922 Feb. 1; 1p
    - CMB -- from J.C. Brooks, 1938 Dec. 2
  - Barber, H.G. (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1909 Dec. 20
  - Barbour, T. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1914 Feb. 24
    - From Boas, 1914 Feb. 18
    - From Boas, 1914 Jan. 23; 2p
    - To Boas, 1914 Feb. 20
  - Barbour, W. Warren (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1941 Aug. 13; 1p
    - From Boas, 1942 Nov. 18; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 Aug. 26; 1p
    - To Boas, 1942 Nov. 20; 1p
  - Barclay, J.F. (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1906 Oct. 22; 4p
  - Barkan, A. (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1905?
  - Barley, F.J. (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1910 Oct. 18; 2p
  - Barlow, J.U. (Box 4)
    - see F. Boas, 1938 Jan.
  - Barlow, Norma (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1938 July 19; 1p
  - Barlow, S.L.M. (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1939 Mar. 30; 1p
      see F. Boas
    - SLMB -- from B.J. Foss, 1939 Sept. 28
    - see F. Boas to O.G. Villard, 1931 May 23
    - SLMB -- from B.J. Foss, 1931 Dec 31
  - Barlow, W.A. (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1915 June 3
  - Barnard College (Box 4)
    - To Boas
      - Notice of Courses, 1902 Nov. 14
      - Appropriation, 1918 Oct.
      - Allotment of funds for dept., 1918 Apr. 19
      - from Braun, W.A., 1923 Apr. 3
      - from Loiseawe, H., 1923 Apr. 8
      - from Baldwin, C.S., 1923 Apr. 9
  - Barnes, Earl (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1894 Dec. 29
  - Barnes, Harry E. (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1918 July 8; 1p
    - To Boas, 1919 Apr. 1; 2p
  - Barnes, Irene (Box 4)
    - Letter of recommendation for, 1928 Mar. 16; 1p
  - Barnes?, J.W. (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1915 June 24; 2p
  - Barnes, Nellie (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1927 Dec. 9; 1p
    - From Boas, 1928 Jan. 26; 1p
    - To Boas, 1927 Dec. 6; 5p
    - To Boas, 1927 Dec. 13; 2p
    - To Boas, 1928 Feb. 16; 2p
  - Barnes, R.P. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1929 Oct. 24; 1p
    - To Boas, 1929 Oct. 23; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931??; 2p
    - To Boas, 1932 Mar. 30; 1p
  - Barnes, W. Anson (Box 4)
    - To Boas, 1896 May 7
  - Barnett,? (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1902 Sept. 25
  - Barnich, G. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 8; 1p
  - Barnum, S.G. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1934 Mar. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1934 Mar. 3; 1p
  - Baron, S.W. (Box 4)
    - From Boas, 1933 June 29; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 June 3; 1p
  - Barr, Alfred H., Jr. (Box 5)
    - To Boas, 1935 Mar. 13; 1p
  - Barret, Laura (Box 5)
    - To Boas, 1938 Feb. 3; 1p
  - Barrett, G.H. (Box 5)
    - To Boas, 1913 May 12
    - G.H.B. -- to Danielson, 1912 July 10; 4p
  - Barrett, H.J. (Box 5)
    - To Boas, 1933 Mar. 1; 1p
      enc. Levinson, S.C.
    - To Boas, 1933 Sept. 20
    - To Boas, 1933 Nov. 17; 1p
  - Barrett, John (Box 5)
    - From Boas, 1907 Oct. 21
    - From Boas, 1907 Oct. 30
    - From Boas, 1907 Nov. 2
    - From Boas, 1907 Dec. 6
    - From Boas, 1907 Dec. 11
    - From Boas, 1907 Dec. 26; 3p
    - From Boas, 1908 Mar. 5
    - From Boas, 1908 Apr. 27
    - From Boas, 1908 May 13; 2p
    - From Boas, 1908 May 21
    - From Boas, 1908 Nov. 29; 2p
    - From Boas, 1910 Nov. 30
    - From Boas, 1910 Dec. 1
    - From Boas, 1910 Dec. 27
    - From Boas, 1911 Jan. 27
    - From Boas, 1913 Jan. 2
    - From Boas, 1915 Nov. 5
    - From Boas, 1920 Sept. 1; 1p
    - To Boas, 1907 May 24
    - To Boas, 1907 Oct. 28
    - To Boas, 1907 Nov. 1
    - To Boas, 1907 Dec. 6
    - To Boas, 1908 Mar. 11
    - To Boas, 1908 Apr. 15
    - To Boas, 1908 May 22
    - To Boas, 1910 Nov. 30
    - To Boas, 1911 Jan. 24
    - To Boas, 1911 Feb. 5
    - To Boas, 1911 Feb. 8
    - To Boas, 1915 Feb. 3
    - To Boas, 1915 Nov. 2
  - Barrett, S.A. (Box 5)
    - 1910 Feb. 26
    - From Boas, 1913 Nov. 26
    - From Boas, 1913 Dec. 10
    - From Boas, 1913 Dec. 17; 2p
    - From Boas, 1914 Jan. 3; 4p
    - From Boas, 1914 Jan. 24
    - From Boas, 1914 Mar. 4; 2p
    - From Boas, 1916 Oct. 20
    - From Boas, 1926 May 1; 1p
    - From Boas, 1926 June 2; 1p
    - From Boas, 1926 June 15; 1p
    - From Boas, 1926 June 23; 1p
    - From Boas, 1942 Apr. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1908 Sept. 14; 2p
    - To Boas, 1908 Sept. 24; 2p
    - To Boas, 1910 Feb. 23; 3p
    - To Boas, 1910 Mar. 7
    - To Boas, 1913 Nov. 29; 2p
    - To Boas, 1913 Dec. 12; 2p
    - To Boas, 1913 Dec. 30; 2p
    - To Boas, 1914 Jan. 27
    - To Boas, 1914 Mar. 2; 2p
    - To Boas, 1916 Oct. 18
    - To Boas, 1926 May 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1926 July 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1942 May 14; 1p
  - Barrows, A.L. (Box 5)
    - From Boas, 1931 Oct. 7; 1p
    - From Boas, 1931 Nov. 24; 1p
    - From Boas, 1932 Dec. 13; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Aug. 28; 1p
    - To Boas, 1932 Dec. 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1932 Dec. 14; 1p
    - enc. with Beckwith, M.W., 1931 Apr. 7
    - ALB -- from Cook, S.J., 1931 Oct. 28
  - Barrows, Alice (Box 5)
    - To Boas, 1939 Mar. 24; 1p
  - Barrows, B.P. (Box 5)
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 22; 1p
  - Barruf, Carl (Barus?) (Box 5)
    - From Boas, 1920 Apr. 9; 1p
  - Barry, F. (Box 5)
    - From Boas, 1933 Mar. 17; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Mar. 1; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Mar. 21; 1p
  - Barry, J. Neilson (Box 5)
    - From Boas, 1933 Jan. 19; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Jan. 13; 4p
    - To Boas, 1933 Jan. 23; 1p
  - Barsky, Edward K. (Box 5)
    - To Boas, 1939 May 31; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 June 8; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 Nov. 1; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 Apr. 24; 1p
    - To Boas, 1941 Feb. 11; 1p
  - Barth, A. (Box 5)
    - From Boas, 1934 July 16; 1p
  - Barth, Dora (Box 5)
    - To Wendriner, K.G., 1938 Dec. 19; 2p
  - Barth, Hans (Box 5)
    - Co-signer of above, 1939 Jan. 9
  - Barth, L.C. (Box 5)
    - from LeCron, J.D., 1940 Jan. 18
  - Bartholdt, Richard (Box 5)
    - From Boas, 1931 Oct. 21; 1p
    - From Boas, 1931 Nov. 6; 1p
    - From Boas, 1931 Nov. 13; 1p
    - From Boas, 1931 Nov. 19; 1p
    - From Boas, 1932 Jan. 20; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Nov. 1; 1p
    - To Boas, 1931 Nov. 17; 1p
  - Barton, R.F. (Box 5)
    - From Boas, 1931 Mar. 4; 1p
    - From Boas, 1940 Dec. 30; 1p
    - To Boas, 1930 July 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1930 Aug. 26; 1p
    - See F.B., 1931 Nov. 22
    - To Boas, 1931 Dec. 31; 3p
    - See Bogoras, W.G., 1931 Feb. 1
    - To Boas, 1940 Nov. 17; 3p
    - To Boas, 1941 Mar. 10; 1p
  - Baruch, Bernard M. (Box 5)
    - See F.B. to Klenze, C. v., 1920 Nov. 24
    - See F.B. to Klenze, C. v., 1936 June 15
  - Baruch, Emanuel (Box 5)
    - From Boas, 1920 Oct. 13; 1p
      with copies to v. Klenze, Camillo; Kayser, C.F.; Busse, A.; Speyer, James; Frank, K.G.; Heuser, F.W.; Lieber, Hugo
    - To Boas, 1906 Mar. 9; 2p
  - Baruch, E. de M. (Box 5)
    - From Boas, 1932 Apr. 7; 1p
  - Baruch, G. (Box 5)
    - 1920 Feb. 12, 2p
  - Barus, Carl (Box 5)
    - From Boas, 1923 Feb. 5; 1p
    - From Boas, 1923 Mar. 2; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Apr. 13; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Aug. 3; 1p
    - To Boas, 1923 Mar. 1; 1p
  - Bary, Adolphe de (Box 5)
    - To Boas, 1905 Feb. 2; 1p
  - Basadre, Jorge (Box 5)
    - From Boas, 1939 June 22; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 June 15; 1p
  - Bashein, Jules (Box 5)
    - To Boas, 1940 June 6; 2p
  - Bassi, Julius (Box 5)
    - From Boas, 1937 Mar. 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 Mar. 11; 1p
  - Bassuk, Albert O. (Box 5)
    - From Boas, 1936 Sept 28; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 June 27; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Aug. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Aug. 17; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Sept 30; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Oct. 1; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Oct. 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 June 22; 1p
    - To Boas, 1938 July 21; 1p
  - Bastian, Adolph (Box 5)
    - From Boas, 1886 Jan. 5
    - From Boas, 1887 Apr. 4
    - To Boas, 1884 Oct. 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1886 Aug. 7
    - To Boas, 1887 Jan.
    - To Boas, 1887 Mar. 1
    - To Boas, 1887 Mar. 30
    - To Boas, 1887 Apr. 25
    - To Boas, 1887 Oct. 21
    - To Boas, 1887 Dec.?; 3p
    - To Boas, 1887 Dec.?; 3p
    - To Boas, 1887 Dec.?; 3p
    - To Boas, 1887 Dec.?; 4p
    - To Boas, 1888 Feb. 3; 3p
    - To Boas, 1888 July 3; 2p
    - To Boas, 1888 Nov. 13; 4p
    - To Boas, 1888 Dec.?; 1p
    - To Boas, 1888 Dec.?; 2p
    - To Boas, 1893??; 3p
    - To Boas, 1893??; 1p
    - To Boas, 1894 Apr. 24; 2p
  - Bastos de Avila, José (Box 5)
    - From Boas, 1938 Feb. 10; 1p
  - Bates, Catherine Lee (Box 5)
    - From Boas, 1920 Apr. 9; 1p
  - Bates, E.S. (Box 5)
    - see McConnell, F.J., 1939 Jan. 30
  - Bates, M.C. (Box 5)
    - To Boas, 1933 Sept 8; 1p
  - Bateson, Gregory (Box 5)
    - To Boas, 1936 Mar. 23; 4p
  - Bateson, Mrs. Gregory (Box 5)
    see Mead, Margaret
  - Bather (Box 5)
    - From Boas, 1907 Aug. 9
    - To Boas, 1907 July 23
  - Batos, Leopoldo (Box 5)
    - From Boas, 1907 Oct. 18
  - Battles, C.A. (Box 5)
    - From Boas, 1937 June 24; 1p
  - Baucalari, I.L. (Box 5)
    - To Boas, 1922 July 12; 5p
  - Bauer, Fritz (Box 5)
    - To Boas, 1922 Sept 18; 6p
    - To Boas, 1923 Jan. 3; 4p
  - Bauer, P.V.C. (Box 5)
    - From Boas, 1922 Nov. 13; 1p
    - P.V.C.B. -- to Gruener, 1922??; 1p
  - Bauer, Walter (Box 5)
    - From Boas, 1939 June 29; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 June 6; 2p
  - Bauer, Wilhelm (Box 5)
    - To Boas, 1920 Oct. 13; 1p
  - Baum, P.F. (Box 5)
    - To Boas, 1917 June 5
  - Baumann, C.C. (Box 5)
    - From Boas, 1905 Nov. 1; 1p
    - From Boas, 1905 Dec. 14; 1p
    - From Boas, 1906 Jan. 5; 1p
    - From Boas, 1906 Feb. 2; 1p
    - To Boas, 1905 Oct. 30; 1p
    - To Boas, 1905 Dec. 28; 2p
    - To Boas, 1906 Jan. 8; 2p
    - To Boas, 1906 Feb. 8; 1p
  - Baumann, H. (Box 5)
    - To Boas, 1933 Jan. 8; 1p
  - Baumann, N. (Box 5)
    - To Boas, 1933 June 6; 1p
  - Baumgarten, F. (Box 5)